Preliminary Inventory to the Metropolitan Council on Housing Records TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series II. Subject Files., 14.0 linear feet
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Riverside Edgecomb Neighborhood Association (RENA), undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Receivership, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Rent Control (City), 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Rent Control (City), 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Rent Control (City), 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Rent Control (City), 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Rent Control (City), 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Rent Control (City), 1961-1967 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Rent Control (City), 1961-1967 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Rent Control (City), 1961-1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Rent Control (City), 1961-1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Rent Control (City), 1961-1967 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Rent Control - Vacancy Decontrol, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Rent Control - Vacancy Decontrol, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Rent Controls, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Rent Controls, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Rent Controls, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Rent Controls, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Rent Controls, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rent Stabilization, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Rent Stabilization, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Rent Stabilization, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Rent Control: Maximum Base Rent (MBR), undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Rent Control: Maximum Base Rent (MBR), undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rent Control (various topics), undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978- 1987 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1983-1986 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1983-1986 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1983-1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1983-1986 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Rent Stabilization, 1983-1986 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Tenant Unity Coalition, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Tenant Unity Coalition, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Tenant Unity Day, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Tenant Unity Day, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Tenant Unity Day, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Tenant Unity Day, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Tenant Unity Day, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Tenants Political Action Committee (TEN PAC), undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tenants Power, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Tenant Survival Conference, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Tenant Teams for Action, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Tenants Union of the Lower East Side, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Tenants United for Affordable Housing (TUFA), undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Third Avenue Coalition, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Tompkins Square, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Tudor City Tenant Association., undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Unaffiliated Columbia Tenants Organization, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - United Public Housing Assn. Of Yonkers, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Unity Party 1983, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Unity Party 1982-3 #1, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Unity Party 1982 #2, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Unity Party 1981 (see also Barbaro), undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Uptown Tenants Council, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Site 30, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Urban Renewal 1989, 1990, 1991, 1992, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Urban Renewal-NYC #1, undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Urban Renewal-NYC #2, undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Urban Renewal-NYC #3, undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Urban Renewal 1976 #4, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Urban Renewal and Public Housing Panel, undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Vietnam, undated (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Warehousing, undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Warehousing, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Warehousing, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Warehousing, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Warehousing, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Warehousing, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Warranty of Habitability #1 (Milano Decision), undated (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Warranty of Habitability #2, undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Washington Heights Tenants Association and Citizens Committee of Washington Heights, undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Washington Square, undated (Box 23, Folder 34)
- Series III. 2002 Accession and Subsequent Accessions through 2007, 39.0 linear feet
  This series contains subject and administrative files relating to the themes covered in Series I and II, and files on Met Council's radio program on WBAI, including audiocassettes of interviews, MCH branch and building organizations and other tenant organizations, including the Cooper Square Committee, East Side Tenants Council, and the Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association, the Neighborhood Preservation Program, squatters, files about Jane Benedict and Esther Rand, and some Spanish language tenant materials.
  - East Side Tenants Council record book (1963)East Side Tenants Council files (late 1970s/early 1980s), 1963, 1970s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Rent Guidelines Board (RGB)/Rent stabilization, MCH's work on, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Housing Court, MCH's work on, 1973, 1975-1976, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Housing Court, MCH's work on, 1984-1985, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Squatters, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - MCH on Public Housing, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Bronx Branch, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Harlem Branch, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Queens Branch, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - West Side Branch, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - West Side Coalition, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Midtown Branch, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - West Village Urban Renewal, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - MCH Urban Renewal, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Wagner on rent control, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Rent control battle, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Price control materials, 1940s (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Daily Compass articles on housing and rent control, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Articles on housing, 1940s-1950s (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - American Labor Party materials on rent and housing, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Leaflets, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Committee to end discrimination in Stuytown pamphlet, 1940s-1950s (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - NY tenant councils, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - West Side Tenant and Consumer Council, undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Tenant Guides, 1939, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Symposium, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Lower East Side newsletter, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Legislative Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Albany and City Hall lobbying - Frances Goldin, committee chair, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - MCH minutes and materials, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Vacant lot and building survey, for book A Citizen's Guide to…, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Cooper Square, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper clippings and reader survey, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1950s-1960s (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Lower East Side branch: includes Stalling campaign, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Letters, minutes, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - 178 East 2nd Street (MCH-organized building, in news), 1974 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - MCH and Civilian Review Board, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Annual conference "Press Panel", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - East Side Tenants Council (Part of MCH), 1950s (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Rent control amendment hearings, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Urban renewal projects (adopted) (Esther Rand's files: letters, clippings, statements), 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Urban renewal sites (dropped) (Esther Rand's file), 1960 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - East Side Tenants Council (Esther Rand's file), 1960 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - NAACP (Esther Rand's file), undated (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - MCH minutes and memoranda (Esther Rand's file), undated (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - East Side papers of Esther Rand and Frances Goldin, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous MCH, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Habitat Forum NYC (Esther Rand), 1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Tenants March on Gracie Mansion, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - NY State Commission to Study Rents, 1977-1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Unity Party (Jane Benedict candidate for governor), 1982 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - National Tenants Union, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - National Tenants Union, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Rent Control Lobbying, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Rent Control Lobbying, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Frances Goldin correspondence, conference programs and flyers, studies etc., 1963-1964 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Early MCH urban renewal fights, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - MCH publications: fact sheets, booklets, manuals, 1960s-1970s (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - MCH publications: fact sheets, booklets, manuals, 1960s-1970s (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Tenant News, 1962-1965 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - MCH and antipoverty programs, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Frances Goldin: correspondence with Roger Start, Councilman Katzman, photo in NY Times, letters-to-the-editor, 1961-1968 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - MCH minutes, drafts, and memos, 1958-1960s (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Organized Tenants, Inc., 1962 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Citywide Council for Better Housing: Jane Benedict, member, Caroline Roest, secretary, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - MCH Trade Union Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes: Housing Crime Trials, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Audio cassettes: WLIB radio show air testsInterviews with organizers of other organizations: Tony Aguilar, Terry Mizrahi, Rima McKay, Mary Daily (NWBCCC), Roger HayesCommunity Board #3 Meeting (May 18, 1993)"Where have all the neighborhoods gone"Building Opening Ceremony, 71 East 4th Street (August 28, 1991), 1990s (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Video cassettes: Lincoln Swados, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Articles and letters-to-the-editor, pro and con, on Jane Benedict, mostly re: profile in "Our Town", undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand: Naturalization papers, marriage artifacts, misc. letters, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Position papers: MCH, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Build Public Housing Committee: MCH, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Annual Assembly, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Conference, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Press, policy statements, 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - WBAI announcement, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Policy statement: Cadman Plaza, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Public Housing Committee, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Press releases, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - NAACP, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous non-MCH, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Washington Square Neighbors, 1950s (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Legislative bulletins, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Legislative Committee, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Squatters: Correspondence, leaflets and articles, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Washington Square Tenants Association, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Washington Square Tenants Council: Correspondence, legal papers, reports of meetings, 1960s (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Yorkville, East Harlem: leaflet masters, undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Central Brooklyn: leaflet masters, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Washington Heights: leaflet masters, undated (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - West Harlem: leaflet, undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - West Queens Branch: Correspondence, articles, undated (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - MCH documents, including:Flyer for state hearing (1986), MCH constitution, Brooklyn branch flyer; Request to speak at budget hearing (1974); Letter to NY Times(1974); Press release (1964); Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) hearing flyer (1986); Undated press release (1970s: Rockefeller); Tenant News(1969); MCH Maximum Base Rent (MBR) flyer (1995); Anti-Giuliani flyer (1997); "A Program for Housing in the Public Domain" flyer (undated); Picket flyer (undated); testimony on NYC NOW program (1992); Testimony on Senior Citizen Rent Increase Exemption (SCRIE) hearing (1992); Testimony on lead paint abatement (1992); Testimony on city-owned building rules (1992), 1970s-1997 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - City Council testimony, letters, etc., 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, including:Meeting minutes (1959); Demo flyer on Masanyk Towers (1968); Letter to editor by Esther Rand re: Senator Robert F. Kennedy's "slum plan", 1959-1968 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Penn Square South, undated (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Cooper Square, 1959-1961 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, including: Letter to Rockefeller (1961); Statement against demolition (early 1960s); Papers of Organized Tenants, Inc (1960); The New York Tenants Association; Lower East Side flyer against Cleary block on Madison Street; Yorkville SOH (1961); Goldin testimony at hearing (1961); Villager article on Jacobs speaking at MCH conference (1961); Housing Emergency Legislation Program (HELP); Opposition to 15% increase (1961); MCH bylaws and constitution (1962); Housing News(1956); Conference pamphlets (1959-1963); Morningside Citizens Committee (1960) (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Housing and Development Board: MCH letters and proposals, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell-Lama, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Bellevue South urban renewal fight, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama Coalition: Barbaro, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Franklin Plaza Tenants Association (Mitchell-Lama) (MCH affiliate), 1970s (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Albany: MCH lobbying trip, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Legislative agendas and Resolutions adopted by Freedom Conference (1963), 1960s (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Urban renewal, rent subsidies, rehabilitation, letters, flyers, etc., undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Ruppert Renewal (Ruppert Brewery Site in Yorkville): MCH organizing and newspaper clippings on renewal site), 1960s-1980s (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Ruppert Renewal (Ruppert Brewery Site in Yorkville): MCH organizing and newspaper clippings on renewal site), 1960s-1980s (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Smoke detectors: Law requiring them and the controversy over ionization-type detectors, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Yorkville Save Our Homes and MCH anti-demolition urban renewal fight in Yorkville: YSOH founding organization of MCH, 1955-1961 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - MCH's first constitution, plus notes from Constitutional Conference (December 5, 1959) (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Gramercy Neighbors, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Housing brochures, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Property owners: Anti-Title I and Rent Control, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Black Struggle: MCH involvement with Congress on Racial Equality (CORE), Urban League, etc., 1962-1965 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Housing Crimes Trial, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Housing Crimes Trial: Newspaper clippings, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Coalition Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP), 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Coalition Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP), 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - MCH Conference, 1981-1982 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - MCH Convention of members, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings and flyers, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Position papers, fact sheets, and flyers, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings on MCH, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - National Tenants Union, Jul 1981 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - No Service, No Love (play produced by MCH at City Hall), 1977 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - NY State Tenants and Neighbors, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell-Lama Committee, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Fundraising/25th Anniversary, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Citywide Rent Strike, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Harlem Branch of MCH, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - MCH 6th Annual Conference, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - MCH letters on urban renewal sites, Title I, Battery Park, etc., 1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand letters to editors, politicians, 1970s (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Esther Rand Legislature file: bills and position on bills, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - City and suburban homes: Flyers, MCH letters, testimony, etc., 1985-1990 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Coalition to Re-Plan the Westside Urban Renewal Area: MCH part of, 1973-1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Conservation (neighborhood conservation program): includes Chelsea Save our Homes and Business Committee (Jane Wood), 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Coalition for a Moratorium on Evictions, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - City Planning: includes Planners for Equal Opportunity, 1970s (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Hall Tenants: Fight to preserve live-in studios at Carnegie Hall, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Engine Company 17: Lower East Side Firehouse, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Committee for Independent Political Action (CIPA), 1966 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (MCH affiliate), 1988-1992 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Morningside Tenants Federation (MCH affiliate), 1971-1985 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Neighbors in Action/Vecinos en Action (MCH affiliate), undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - MCH publication from Wagner administration, 1960s (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Yorkville Save Our Homes brochure, 1950s? (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Rent Strikes, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Rent Strikes: Newsletters and leaflets, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Rent Strikes: General material, 1973-1975 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Rent Strikes, 1970s (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Rent Strikes, 1980s (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Branch and building files: Bronx, Brooklyn, East Side;Building files: East Side, 1980s-1990s (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Midtown branch files, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - East Side building files, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - East Side and West Side building files, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - East Side Tenants Council;Lower East Side branch and building files, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Bronx and Brooklyn building files, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Grand Concourse (Bronx), Queens, and Midtown building files, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side building files, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - East Side branch and building files, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - RENA, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and flyers, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Analysis of Rent Control from the tenant's viewpoint, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Lenox Terrace clippings file (before buildings were built), undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous MCH, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Legislation materials (MCH), 1960s (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - MCH statement before City Planning Commission on Battery Park City, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - MCH statement before City Planning Commission on Tompkins Square Area, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - MCH Executive Board minutes and notices, 1960-1961 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - MCH Constitution and Bylaws, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Tompkins Square Project: Urban Renewal, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - MCH publications, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - MCH statements, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Statements on relocation: public proposals, undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Vacant land, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Seward Park extension, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Renewal Proposals: Articles for Brooklyn, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Conference literature, undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - MCH Annual conference, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Lower East Side Neighborhood Association, undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Cooper Square Committee, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Urban Renewal Panel, undated (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Participation Loan, undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Park West Village, undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - MCH 25th Anniversary, undated (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Bay Ridge Branch, undated (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Homefront: Abandonment report, undated (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Bay Ridge Branch, undated (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Lower East Side Masters, undated (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - June 23, undated (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Rent Guidelines Board flyer, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Anti-Warehousing Demo, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - Rent Guidelines Board, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Rent Law, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 46)
  - Workshop on "Spiegel Law", undated (Box 43, Folder 47)